<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Michael Davie's Blog</title><link>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Michael Davie's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backups and Photo Management</title><link>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/backups-photo-management/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/backups-photo-management/</guid><description>Backups and Photo Management I have spent entirely too much time over the years thinking about and tinkering with systems for backing up our data and managing our photos. This post documents the current state of things.
Backups Unsurprisingly, our iPhones and iPads back up to iCloud. We have 200 GB of shared storage for the family as part of our Apple One subscription, which is more than enough.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Technologies</title><link>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/privacy-tech/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/privacy-tech/</guid><description>Privacy Technologies A few years ago I read Tim Wu&amp;rsquo;s excellent book, The Attention Merchants, which opened my eyes to the pervasiveness of what&amp;rsquo;s become known as surveillance capitalism. (The documentary The Social Dilemma also did a great job of highlighting this problem.) Afterward, I basically declared war on advertising in our family&amp;rsquo;s lives, and deployed a number of technologies on our devices and our home LAN to block as much of it as possible.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a blog</title><link>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michaeldavie.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid><description>Setting up a blog A couple hours ago I thought that I should set up a blog, and it&amp;rsquo;s already up and running. Fortunately I already had some of the pieces in place (like a Github account and the domain name), but the whole thing was surprisingly simple. Here are the tools that helped:
Hugo - Static website generator Clean White Theme for Hugo - Simple blog theme Github Pages - Free hosting from Github Github Actions - Automated workflows triggered on code changes Github Actions for Hugo - Workflow to execute Hugo&amp;rsquo;s build and update the site Cloudflare DNS - DNS resolution for my domain Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt - Free TLS certificate, managed by Github</description></item></channel></rss>